ELIAS SPECTOR-ZABUSKY

SUMMARY

Software engineer and musician working with the MERN stack, with an interest in backend development, full stack development, and product work. Previous experience in project management, operations, and the arts. Strong skills in creative problem-solving and collaboration. Analytically minded with a knack for supporting decision-making.

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Sept. 2023 – Present

ENGAGE PARTNERS; REMOTE

Develop features and implement site integrations in **TypeScript** and **React** for a text content generator web extension (<u>Click2.ai</u>) powered by generative AI. Provide project management for the development team.

- Designed and built the post generator and integrated this component with LinkedIn and Twitter.
- Iteratively extend settings page to add support for further use cases and per-user configuration.
- Implemented reusable library functions for dynamic, site-agnostic menu rendering to streamline future domain integrations and ensure quick and efficient customizations for new applications.

PROFESSIONAL MUSICIAN

Nov. 2015 – Present

FREELANCE; NEW YORK, NEW YORK

Band-member, producer, songwriter, and/or arranger for a few NYC-based bands. www.stolenjars.com

DIGITAL CONTENT AND MERCHANDISE MANAGER

Nov. 2020 – Jan. 2023

ROBIN BARON DESIGN; NEW YORK, NEW YORK

Spearheaded product operations and served as Shopify admin for an interior designer's eCommerce business.

- Utilized HTML and CSS to maintain and customize site, including developing CSS features for the blog.
- Managed 8-10 freelancers in the upload of 12,500+ SKUs from ~40 vendors in line with growth roadmap.

PROJECTS

FRAiME | github.com/ColdWeatherBoyy/Fraime | www.FRAiMED.art

Full Stack Developer. FRAiME is an in-development eCommerce site, leveraging OpenAI's text-to-image DALL-E API to allow users to generate unique art and order prints. **MERN**, **Next.js**, **Styled Components**

- Co-planned the backend architecture; built majority of REST API endpoints and DB models.
- Improved state management to decrease DB calls by moving data from global context to caching.

Chattitude | github.com/ColdWeatherBoyy/Chattitude | chattitude-44756dc57837.herokuapp.com/

Full Stack Developer. Chattitude is a global messaging app. It offers a chat page for all users, full account persistence and updateability, and chat history. WebSockets, Node.js, MongoDB, React, Express, Chakra UI

- Implemented user authentication using JWT, bcrypt, and HTTP-only cookies as a learning experience.
- Developed functionality for WebSocket front/back-end handshake to track active users and connections.
- Built systems for persisting accounts and chat history and connected them through REST API endpoints.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages/Technologies: JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL, GraphQL, HTML5, CSS3

Backend: Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, MySQL, Sequelize

Frontend: React, Chakra UI, Next.js, Bootstrap

Misc. Tools: Figma, Insomnia, Git, GitHub, Jest, MS Excel, Google Analytics, Shopify

EDUCATION

COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY, NEW YORK, NEW YORK

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

HARVARD BUSINESS SCHOOL ONLINE

Feb. 2023 – Apr. 2023

Jan. 2023 – Apr. 2023

Certificate in Business Analytics

BROWN UNIVERSITY, PROVIDENCE, RHODE ISLAND

2011 - 2015

Bachelor of Arts in Theatre Arts and Performance Studies Phi Beta Kappa; T. Carpenter Elocution Award